What order did you come up with
for the six types of operators?
Here is the correct order of
preference, from top to bottom:
Arithmetic
Containment
Comparison
Identity
Logical
Assignments
Remember that parentheses supersede all
operators when looking at any calculation
or comparison. For the logical operators,
not takes precedence over and, which takes
precedence over or. And for arithmetic,
the order of operations is as follows:
Parentheses
Exponents
Multiplication
Division
Addition
Subtraction
And, as a friendly reminder, you have a mnemonic
on this one: Please Excuse My Dear Aunt Sally. To
finish this unit, let’s look at one example of a
calculation involving multiple facets of the six
types of operators. I have the 136-analyze file
open and we want to determine if the result is
true or false. In these situations, look over
the types of operators you have. Here we have
assignment, comparison, arithmetic, logical,
containment, and identity. Arithmetic happens
first, so, using a comment on line 5, I will
add 3 and 2 to get x = 5. Containment is next,
and y is in 1, 2, 3, so that is true.
Comparison is next. X = 5, so that is
true. Identity is next. X is not y. That is true.
What’s left? Logical. All the results are true,
so the result, the assignment is true and when
I run this code, indeed, the result is true.